NICHOLAS KEMPKES

Software Engineer

Clarksville, TN 37043 (218) 770-3673

nicholas.kempkes@gmail.com https://nicholaskempkes.com

SUMMARY

Highly motivated software engineer with expertise in full-stack software applications development using JavaScript, React, Node.js, Express.js, SQL, NoSQL, and AWS. In addition to my technical skills, I hold a Bachelor's degree in Technical Management: Project Management and am currently pursuing a second Bachelor's degree in Information Technology: Programming with a focus on programming languages and software development. With experience as an Air Force veteran and former Geospatial Intelligence analyst, I possess strong analytical and problem-solving skills. I am dedicated to creating efficient and user-friendly software solutions that meet business needs.

EDUCATION -

American Public University Credit Hours: 91 / 121 B.S. Information Technology: Programming

Galvanize: Hack Reactor

August 2022

Certificate: Advanced Software

Engineering

American Public University January 2019 GPA 3.7478

B.A.S. Technical Management: Project Management

KEY SKILLS —

Front End | JavaScript (ES5 and ES6), React.js, HTML, CSS, Redux, JQuery, JSON

Backend | Node.js, Express, MongoDB, Mongoose, MySQL, RESTful API Development, PostgreSQL

Testing / Deployment | Jest, Mocha, Chai, AWS: EC2 / RDS / S3, K6, Loader.io

Developer Tools | Git, npm, Webpack, Babel, Agile Methodology, Scrum, TDD, PGadmin, Postman, Google API

Languages in Progress | Java, Typescript

EXPERIENCE

December 2022

Freelance • Full Stack Developer • www.wagsandwalkies.dog

Pet care services website including contact component, gallery, and customer testimonials. Utilized CSS animations and SVG elements to create visually appealing and modern design elements, such as waves and other design flourishes.

August 2022 – December 2022

Software Engineering Immersive Resident • Full Stack Engineer • Galvanize: Hack Reactor

Mentored 308 students on full stack development with React/Node,js. Aided students with troubleshooting/debugging and contributed to performance reports for student progress. Built strong relationships with students that extended beyond contracted employment.

August 2022

Full Stack Engineer • Personal Project: Job Searching Application
Implemented Google services to include Calendar and Geocoding APIs along
with PostgreSQL Geo-extensions for advanced calendar and location-based
features. Assisted in development of multi-page React application utilizing
routing options for different account types.

July 2022

Software Engineer • Personal Project: E-commerce API Restructuring / Optimization

Scalable RESTful API built with Express.js and PostgreSQL designed to replace existing poor performing API and retain data shape to existing front end application. Utilized optimization techniques to improve performance and reduce server load, resulting in a capacity of 1,800 requests per second on single deployed instance exceeding client requirements.

June 2019 – August 2021
Professional Driver • Boyle Transportation • Billerica, MA

April 2017 – January 2019 Electronics Associate • Wal-Mart • Ash Flat, AR

January 2011 – October 2016 Geospatial Analyst • U.S. Air Force